<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Modelling of a UAV Gimbal Rig Testbench</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/testbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/testbench/</guid>
      <description>The gimbal rig setup for a three degrees of freedom (3 DOF) system represents a cornerstone in the field of rotational mechanics and control systems. This configuration, often visualized through the classic example of a gyroscope, allows for precise manipulation and measurement of an object&amp;rsquo;s orientation in three-dimensional space. By employing a series of nested gimbals—each capable of independent rotation around orthogonal axes—this setup provides a robust framework for exploring complex rotational dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aruco Tag detection using OpenCV and Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/a-simple-opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/a-simple-opencv/</guid>
      <description>Aruco Tag, also known as AR Tag, is widely used in navigation and tracking purposes in robotics field. With machine learning and modern image processing techniques, it is not difficult to detect and identify AR tags. However, in this post, I will try to use the most basic image processing tools of OpenCV for the approach to that problem.&#xA;Problem Statement There are four photos of random settings where there are posters containing the AR Tags.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
