<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical Modelling of a UAV Gimbal Rig Testbench</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/testbench/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/testbench/</guid>
      <description>The gimbal rig setup for a three degrees of freedom (3 DOF) system represents a cornerstone in the field of rotational mechanics and control systems. This configuration, often visualized through the classic example of a gyroscope, allows for precise manipulation and measurement of an object&amp;rsquo;s orientation in three-dimensional space. By employing a series of nested gimbals—each capable of independent rotation around orthogonal axes—this setup provides a robust framework for exploring complex rotational dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aruco Tag detection using OpenCV and Python</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/a-simple-opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/a-simple-opencv/</guid>
      <description>Aruco Tag, also known as AR Tag, is widely used in navigation and tracking purposes in robotics field. With machine learning and modern image processing techniques, it is not difficult to detect and identify AR tags. However, in this post, I will try to use the most basic image processing tools of OpenCV for the approach to that problem. Let&amp;rsquo;s break down the code in segments for understanding it better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there! This is Ahmed Imtiaz Ferdous. Welcome to my personal website.&#xA;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I graduated as a Mechanical Engineer. Currently, I am looking forward to research opportunities. My research interests are primarily focused on Robotics and Control Theory. I have always been passionate about how abstract mathematics can control the physical reality. I have been studying mechanical engineering while trying to learn coding by myself and involving myself in hands-on experience on robotics, which made me more resolute on my pursuit.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
